Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/sang-nguyen-thanh (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Natural Language Processing (NLP)
Large Language Models (LLM)
Machine Learning

Certifications

ChatGPT Prompt Engineering for Developers

Deep Learning Specialization Machine Learning

Honors-Awards

Scholarship from Faculty of Electrical & Electronics Engineering – 2019, for students having active participation in extracurricular activities

Sang Nguyen Thanh

Al Scientists at FPT Corporation

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Summary

Currently, I am working as an AI engineer, especially applying Deep Learning models to solve Computer Vision (CV), Natural Language Processing (NLP), and Optical Character Recognition (OCR) tasks. My experience spans diverse industries, such as healthcare, bank, and defective images, allowing me to effectively apply my expertise to various domains. I am a continuous learner, staying current with AI research and trends, always ready to explore new cool stuff, then deploy them into real-life applications.

Experience

FPT Corporation

Al Scientist

December 2022 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Build OCR system to extract sphygmomanometer and blood glucose meter information.
- Build healthcare chatbot based on Knowledge Graph (KG)
- Build Scan CV AI core

MINERVA TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS JSC

Al Research And Development Engineer May 2022 - November 2022 (7 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Building AI models and developing OCR solutions to deploy on eKYC API system.
- Researching and developing Generative Dialogue System (Generative CHATBOT), build-up from basic (RNN, LSTM) to State of the art - SOTA (Transformer, GPT2) sequence models.

Emage Development
Artificial Intelligence Engineer
November 2020 - May 2022 (1 year 7 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Researching (reading, implementing and improving on papers) on Deep Learning techniques for Computer Vision tasks.
- Building AI models and developing computer vision solutions to classify, recognize defective industrial products.
- Collaborating with the Software team to communicate between application and Python backend.

Education

Ho Chi Minh University of Technology
Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Electrical and Electronics
Engineering · (2016 - 2020)